<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Migration on Stratos Gerakakis</title>
    <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/tags/migration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Migration on Stratos Gerakakis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 14:26:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://stratos.gerakakis.net/tags/migration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Arch</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2014/08/moving_to_arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 14:26:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2014/08/moving_to_arch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well the time to move-on has finally come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being a faithfull Ubuntu user since Warty Warthog, Ubuntu 4.10 back in 2004, (wow, already a decade ago) it is time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are multiple online posts complaining about the direction Ubuntu has taken over the last years, but I&amp;rsquo;ll just quickly state my own reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tired of constantly upgrading the system every six months. Although considerable effort is being taken to provide smooth upgrades, usually the procedure to upgrade a system takes the better part of a day.  That is, if everything goes well.  After almost 20 upgrades I had some gone awry on me, which really adds to the burden of updating the system.  And that&amp;rsquo;s only for one system.  Multiply that be 5-6 times, for all my servers, desktops, laptops and the amount of work really adds up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever since the move to Unity (which I don&amp;rsquo;t like at all) I have been using Gnome3.  With Ubuntu I am forced to stay a couple of version behind, since the repositories do not include the latest version.  Some thing with other packages that do not have the latest versions updated in the repos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last two or three Ubuntu releases I get a lot of &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, Ubuntu has experienced an internal error&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; popups that are really annoying.  Same hardware, same settings but a lot of these errors.  And very vague descriptions of what went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decide it is time to move to another distro.  Reading many nice things online about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.archlinux.org/&#34;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt; and after trying it in a Virtualbox machine I decided to take the plunge.  I took a shortcut though, and installed &lt;a href=&#34;http://antergos.com/&#34;&gt;Antergos&lt;/a&gt; which is a very nicely packaged version of Arch with a gui installer that automatically installs a Desktop Environemnt for you.  All done in &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/The_Arch_Way&#34;&gt;the Arch way&lt;/a&gt; so the end result is well documented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More posts as the time passes by&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>