<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stratos Gerakakis</title>
    <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stratos Gerakakis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 14:26:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://stratos.gerakakis.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Arch</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2014/08/moving_to_arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 14:26:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2014/08/moving_to_arch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well the time to move-on has finally come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being a faithfull Ubuntu user since Warty Warthog, Ubuntu 4.10 back in 2004, (wow, already a decade ago) it is time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are multiple online posts complaining about the direction Ubuntu has taken over the last years, but I&amp;rsquo;ll just quickly state my own reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tired of constantly upgrading the system every six months. Although considerable effort is being taken to provide smooth upgrades, usually the procedure to upgrade a system takes the better part of a day.  That is, if everything goes well.  After almost 20 upgrades I had some gone awry on me, which really adds to the burden of updating the system.  And that&amp;rsquo;s only for one system.  Multiply that be 5-6 times, for all my servers, desktops, laptops and the amount of work really adds up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever since the move to Unity (which I don&amp;rsquo;t like at all) I have been using Gnome3.  With Ubuntu I am forced to stay a couple of version behind, since the repositories do not include the latest version.  Some thing with other packages that do not have the latest versions updated in the repos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last two or three Ubuntu releases I get a lot of &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, Ubuntu has experienced an internal error&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; popups that are really annoying.  Same hardware, same settings but a lot of these errors.  And very vague descriptions of what went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decide it is time to move to another distro.  Reading many nice things online about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.archlinux.org/&#34;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt; and after trying it in a Virtualbox machine I decided to take the plunge.  I took a shortcut though, and installed &lt;a href=&#34;http://antergos.com/&#34;&gt;Antergos&lt;/a&gt; which is a very nicely packaged version of Arch with a gui installer that automatically installs a Desktop Environemnt for you.  All done in &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/The_Arch_Way&#34;&gt;the Arch way&lt;/a&gt; so the end result is well documented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More posts as the time passes by&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Left Hand Of Darkness</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/left_hand_of_darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/left_hand_of_darkness/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/8/88/TheLeftHandOfDarkness1stEd.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter is an Earth-like planet with two major differences: conditions are semi artic even at the warmest time of the year, and the inhabitants are all of the same sex. Tucked away in a remote corner of the universe, they have no knowledge of space travel or of life beyond their own world. And when a strange envoy from space brings news of a vast coalition of planets which they are invited to join, he is met with fear, mistrust and disbelief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(From the book&amp;rsquo;s back cover)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I barely had enough patience to finish this book. I wonder how come it got both the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nebula_Award&#34;&gt;Nebula&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hugo_Award&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; awards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was so special about the a single man trying to convince a newly discovered planet to join the Ekoumen (from the Greek word &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oikoumene&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;οικουμένη&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;)? It could have been vastly more interesting, but the pace and the subject matter of the character conversations were a complete turn off for me. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait for the book to finish. Good thing it was a short one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a nice Ursulla Le Guin book, you&amp;rsquo;re better off with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Earthsea&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Earthsea Trilogy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this site</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are the mesonoxian inaniloquent ramblings of Stratos Gerakakis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This must be the sixth or sevent attempt trying to find the right tool for my online ramblings (after trying, html pages, Geeklog, Drupal, Blogger, Dokuwiki, Nikola, Tinkerer, Pelican)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually I go with by the handle &lt;strong&gt;stratosgear&lt;/strong&gt; and you can find me with that username on &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/stratosgear&#34; title=&#34;Bitbucket&#34;&gt;Bitbucket&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stratosgear&#34; title=&#34;Github&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/stratosgear&#34; title=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/+StratosGerakakis&#34; title=&#34;Google+&#34;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; or other services.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biography</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/bio/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;style&gt;
.post h3 {
  border-bottom: 2px solid grey;
  padding-top: 0.5em;
}
.post h4 {
  margin-bottom: 0;
  margin-top: 1em;
}
.post h5 {
  margin-bottom: 0;
}
.post ul {
  margin-bottom: 0.5em;
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is pulled from the latest version of my info on LinkedIn, right after they got acquired by Microsoft on Jul 2016. Just the &lt;em&gt;straw&lt;/em&gt; that broke the camel&amp;rsquo;s back, that was the required nudge to make me drop LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing valuable there anyways, except constant headhunter requests to get linked, and an &lt;strong&gt;awfull&lt;/strong&gt; LinkedIn interface to &amp;ldquo;trick&amp;rdquo; you into linking with any stranger there and ever increasing pathetic attempts to make you a paying customer by an ever increasing removal of features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judging from the fate of Skype, Sunrise, SwiftKey(?) this won&amp;rsquo;t be getting any better now anyways, so&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application Developer and Project Manager in a wide variety of web based projects and back end server solutions. Many years of experience producing well structured code and managing small teams of developers, providing elegant solutions to intimidating problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;experience:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;planetek-hellas:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Planetek Hellas&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service Manager, Technical Lead, Senior Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;November 2013 – Present (2 years 8 months)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Madrid Area, Spain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working onsite ESAC, ESA (European Space Astronomy Center, European Space Agency), Madrid, Spain​, as a Service Manager and Technical lead for Planetek Hellas ESA projects.​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;saps:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;SAPS&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;cience &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;rchives &lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;ublication &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;ystem is a rich Internet Application that aims to provide an automated process of linking scientific publications with ESA&amp;rsquo;s astrophysics and planetary Missions and Observations, as well as business analytics based on the generated information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Java based development based on Spring based backend running on Tomcat and Google GWT as the frontend, backed by Postgresql database, with searching capabilities provided by ElasticSearch and integration with multiple ESAC Archive AIO systems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;plaavi:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;PLAAVI&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PLA&lt;/strong&gt;nck &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;dded &lt;strong&gt;V&lt;/strong&gt;alue &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;nterfaces Project with the intention to allow users to apply various post-processing to PLANCK data before downloading them from the Planck Legacy Archive (PLA) hosted at ESAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The functionality of the PLAAVI will also allow users to reprocess the science data in a manner different from what is done by the Planck data processing centre and thereby generate their own products. A list of the available Added Vale Interfaces (AVIs) provided will be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noise Map Cut-out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective Beam Averaging on Map Cut-out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit Conversions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color Corrections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planck Sky Model (PSM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map Making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Component Separation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All infrastructure running on clustered installation of Docker containers and integrated with the existing PLA archive website​&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python based development of a distributed service oriented system, backed a fully restful API server and MongoDB, Redis with dashboards provided by Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;startup-company:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Startup Company&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Lead, Senior Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;February 2013 – October 2013 (9 months)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Athens, Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building an online e-commerce site for airline and hotel ticket reservations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration to third party services through SOAP web services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple backend cache systems (memcache, ElasticSearch, Redis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hosted on Amazon EC2. Clustered implementation through multiple application and cache servers. Database in Amazon RDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faceted search interface with Jquery, ElasticSearch, Twitter Bootstrap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project was developed in Symfony2 PHP framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;airtickets-gr:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;airtickets.gr&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Senior Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;August 2012 – November 2012 (4 months)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Athens, Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead Engineer responsible for architecting and implementing a Java backend service to integrate web service communications with Amadeus CRS/GDS (Computer Reservation System, Global Distribution System).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented optimized workflow in order to minimize amount of communication between travel agency and reservations system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Successfully passed the implemented solution through the Amadeus certification process before the system can be taken online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work was done with Java, with Spring framework and Apache Axis Soap protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;peopleperhour-com:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;PeoplePerHour.com&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;March 2012 – July 2012 (5 months)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Athens, Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked developing a caching and indexing service based on Solr (search and indexing service based on Apache Lucene).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed formulas for scoring and boosting results, calculating facets and implementing fuzzy searches on autocomplete text boxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also optimized various parts of the website using memcache techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding was done in PHP with the Yii PHP framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;evorad:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Evorad&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development Manager&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;September 2006 – May 2011 (4 years 9 months)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Athens, Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent knowledge of both RIS and PACS workflows and requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed algorithms for image orientation, multi-parameter series synchronization, MPR and MIP calculations, image annotations, image sorting, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed automated appointment scheduler for medical appointments, server based CD/DVD burning solution, customized integration with customer’s HIS systems, DICOM study auto-forwarding, customized DICOM worklist integration, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project was Java based with Swing GUI&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;emphasis-systems:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Emphasis Systems&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consultant / Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;April 2003 – August 2006 (3 years 5 months)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Athens, Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participation as software engineer in the project Weight Info (Java servlets, JADE ontologies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participation as software engineer in the project eRemedy (Java user interface applet, hardware-software interaction, telemedicine environment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projects:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/PTfjm&#34; title=&#34;Care-paths&#34;&gt;CARE-PATHS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/zWnCn&#34; title=&#34;Carditis&#34;&gt;Carditis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/PTfjm&#34; title=&#34;Weight-Info&#34;&gt;Weight-Info&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/DYb9O&#34; title=&#34;E-Remedy&#34;&gt;E-Remedy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;intergraphics:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Intergraphics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Design Instructor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;February 2001 – March 2002 (1 year 2 months)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Athens, Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instructor for Web Design classes, teaching HTML and Flash Actionscript.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;mediterranean-agronomic-institute-of-chania:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Chania&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;February 2000 – February 2001 (1 year 1 month)&lt;/em&gt;
Chania, Crete, Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed and implemented the Institute&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed the intranet so that the departmnets could share information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed the Herbarium Management system (TCL/TK based).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;encommerce-inc-entrust:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;enCommerce Inc / Entrust&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;December 1996 – November 1999 (3 years)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sunnyvale, CA, USA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acted as the main engineer for all Graphical User Interface efforts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed the Administration Application GUI for getAccess (enCommerce main product).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Researched and eventually developed concurrent GUI and CLI (Command Line Interface) for the same product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the graphical representation of the topology mapping of a network distributed installation of getAccess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead Engineer in localization to Japanese.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;kapalua-consulting:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Kapalua Consulting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consultant / Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;July 1996 – December 1996 (6 months)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sunnyvale, CA, USA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed and supported a travel agency web site using HTML and Perl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed and supported various versions of web servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;university-of-san-francisco:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;University of San Francisco&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Systems Programming TA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;January 1992 – May 1992 (5 months)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
San Francisco, CA, USA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created role model answers of the given projects to be used as reference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintained office hours to assist students with their homework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read and corrected lab assignments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;courses:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Courses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;evorad-1:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Evorad&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oracle Healthcare Transaction Base (HTB) Training&lt;br /&gt;
(16-20 November, 2009)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;skills:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(In strictly alphabetical order)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile, Agile Methodologies, AJAX, Amadeus GDS, Amazon Web Services, Apache, Bash, BIRT, CSS, Distributed Systems, Docker, Drupal, Eclipse, ElasticSearch, Git, Google App Engine, Hibernate, HTML 5, Integration, Jasper Reports, Java, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, Kibana, Linux, Logstash, Mercurial, MySQL, OOP, Perl, PHP, PostgreSQL, Python, Rancher, REST, Smarty, SOAP, Solr, Spring, Subversion, Symfony, TeamCity, Web Applications, Web Development, Web Services, wxPython, Yii, ZeroMQ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;certifications:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Certifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PADI Open Water Diver&lt;br /&gt;
PADI, License 991170****&lt;br /&gt;
May 1999&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;education:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;University of San Francisco&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s, Computer Science, Mathematics Minor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
1989 – 1994&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eniaio Polykladiko Lykeio at Chania&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;High School degree&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
1986 – 1988&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;languages:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Languages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greek&lt;/strong&gt;: Native or bilingual proficiency&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;: Native or bilingual proficiency&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Spanish&lt;/strong&gt;: Elementary proficiency&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-info:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Additional Info&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;interests:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Interests&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Board Games, Reading, Music, Bicycling, Traveling, Scuba diving, Digital Photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;personal-details:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Personal Details&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Birthday: 1970&lt;br /&gt;
Marital Status: Married&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;advice-for-contacting-stratos:541edf880cc61d1f4ca4d7d05824fa74&#34;&gt;Advice for Contacting Stratos&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note: I only link with people that I personally know and have met. I&amp;rsquo;m not linking with random people, and the only exception is for people who are properly introduced to me by a common acquaintance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your linkedin invitation will be brutally rejected otherwise, so brace for it. Have a nice day :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mysql Bindings in Django</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/12/mysql_bindings_in_django/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/12/mysql_bindings_in_django/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to correctly install mysql bindings in a Django virtualenv you need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First install some Ubuntu dependencies::&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo aptitude install build-essential python-mysqldb libmysqlclient-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then create the virtual env and install the python packages::&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ virtualenv --no-site-packages --distribute myVirtualEnv
$ pip install -E myVirtualEnv Django
$ pip install -E myVirtualEnv mysql-python
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was missing the &lt;strong&gt;libmysqlclient-dev&lt;/strong&gt; package and I was getting a &lt;strong&gt;EnvironmentError: mysql_config not found&lt;/strong&gt; when running the &lt;strong&gt;pip install mysql-python&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating a PDF</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/12/translating_a_pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/12/translating_a_pdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, if you pass the link of the online PDF document to the Google Translate service then Google will extract the text from the PDF and translate it in the language that you selected.  It doesn&amp;rsquo;t keep the &lt;strong&gt;exact same&lt;/strong&gt; page formatting but the PDF is now &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; readable.  Much more readable than it was before&amp;hellip; :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ringworld</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/ringworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/ringworld/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!--- 0575077026 --&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/7/71/Ringworld%281stEd%29.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Ringworld&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;No wonder this has won both Hugo and Nebula awards in &lt;sup&gt;1970&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;71&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not very fond of Niven&amp;rsquo;s writing style (this is the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Larry_Niven&#34;&gt;Larry Niven&lt;/a&gt; book I read) and maybe he used it for this book only.  The plot though was ingenious.  The idea of the Ringworld was very interesting. It kept me entertained from the beginning until the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended! :-)  Read more about the plot on [wikipedia][].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[wikipedia]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ringworld&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ringworld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Enough for Love</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/time_enough_for_love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/time_enough_for_love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!--- 0441810764 --&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/6/68/Time_Enough_For_Love_73.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Time Enough for Love&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lazarus Long&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1916-4272&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The capstone and crowning achievement of Heinlein&amp;rsquo;s famous Future History, TIME ENOUGH FOR LOVE follows Lazarus Long through a vast and magnificent timescape of centuries and worlds.Heinlein&amp;rsquo;s longest and most ambitious work, it is the story of a man so in love with Life that he refused to stop living it; and so in love with Time that he became his own ancestor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(From the books back cover)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Heimlein is one of my favorite authors. &amp;ldquo;Time enough for Love&amp;rdquo; was nominated for the Nebula Award for Best Novel (1973) and the Hugo and Locus Awards (1974) and although did not finally win, nonetheless it is quite an interesting read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I cannot outdo the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_Enough_for_Love&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; about the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First overhead ISS pass</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/09/first_overhead_iss_pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/09/first_overhead_iss_pass/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://stratos.gerakakis.net/images/iss.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;International Space Station&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Today I saw my first overhead pass of the ISS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some time I was registered to [Twisst][] and I was receiving their notifications on Twitter but I never actually bothered to really look up and see the station fly overhead.  Well, in my defense, living in Athens, with all this light pollution you can barely see the sky and the stars, so I was waiting for the right opportunity before I actually tried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, today at 20:52 (right as Twisst predicted) I saw the ISS. The brightness was supposed to be at a magnitude of -1.6 (I have no idea how bright that is) and I was wondering what was I was supposed to be looking at.  Suddenly, approximately where I was looking at, a very bright star appeared out of nowhere.  And I could see it with a naked eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was brighter than the other current stars I could see at the moment and it moved at a pretty high speed accross the sky.  It looked like an airplane was flying overhead, but at a quite fast pace.  The whole pass took approximately 5 minutes and the station traversed an arc almost two thirds of the sky. Then, slowly, in 5-6 seconds, while it was still moving, faded out to nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must have look like an idiot, standing there in the middle of the park (it was Azul&amp;rsquo;s nightly walk) gazing at the sky for five minutes.  But, I think it was worth it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Twisst]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twisst.nl&#34;&gt;http://www.twisst.nl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stratos?ear.com word play</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/06/stratos_ear_com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/06/stratos_ear_com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny how many of the following domain names are actually working (and how many of the letter combinations actually make sense):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Domain&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Valid Word&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Domain Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosaear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosbear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratoscear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosdear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratoseear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exists&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosfear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Obviously&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosgear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exists&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratoshear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosiear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosjear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratoskear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exists&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratoslear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosmear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosnear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosoear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratospear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosqear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosrear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratossear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratostear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosuear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosvear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exists&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratoswear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosxear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratosyear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;www.stratoszear.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Edited):&lt;/strong&gt; This post was written when the blog was hosted on www.stratosgear.com.  I have long since moved it to the current location. &lt;em&gt;&amp;ndash;Aug 14 2014&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmote more 4 us</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/05/cosmote_more_4_us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/05/cosmote_more_4_us/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://stratos.gerakakis.net/images/cosmote_more4us.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Cosmote more 4 us&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Ξαφνικά άρχισαν να μου έρχονται κάποια SMS στο καρτοκινητό μου ότι:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ΜΟΛΙΣ ΣΥΝΔΕΘΗΚΕΣ ΣΤΟ INTERNET ΜΕ ΧΡΕΩΣΗ 1Ε ΓΙΑ 24 ΩΡΕΣ. ΜΠΟΡΕΙΣ ΝΑ ΣΕΡΦΑΡΕΙΣ ΑΠΕΡΙΟΡΙΣΤΑ ΑΠΟ ΤΟ ΚΙΝΗΤΟ ΣΟY ΜΕΧΡΙ ΤΙΣ 22/05/11 11:45 ΧΩΡΙΣ ΕΠΙΠΛΕΟΝ ΧΡΕΩΣΗ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Στην αρχή νόμιζα ότι έκανα εγώ κάποιο λάθος, αλλά σήμερα διασταύρωσα με την αδερφή μου ότι γίνεται και σε εκείνην το ίδιο.  Σε αυτήν είχαν ήδη χρεώσει περίπου 20 ευρώ και όταν πήρε τηλέφωνο την εξυπηρέτηση πελατών της είπαν ότι είναι μια καινούρια υπηρεσία της Cosmote και αν δεν την θέλει μπορεί να την απενεργοποιήσει.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Συγνώμη!!! Με ρώτησε κανείς εμένα αν θέλω αυτήν την &amp;ldquo;καινούρια υπηρεσία&amp;rdquo; πριν αρχίσουν να μου την χρεώνουν; Έστειλα εγώ κανένα SMS ενεργοποίησης πουθενά;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ποιός ξέρει πόσα παράνομα τέτοια ευρώ έχει μαζέψει η Cosmote με αυτήν την απάτη.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Έλεος&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Update 1η Ιουνίου 2011]:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Μετά από λίγο googling βρήκα τα εξής:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Αυτή η υπηρεσία λέγεται &lt;strong&gt;Cosmote Internet Day Pass&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Σύμφωνα με τα λεγόμενα τους:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Η υπηρεσία COSMOTE Internet Day Pass είναι προενεργοποιημένη σε όλους τους συνδρομητές Συμβολαίου, ΚαρτοΣυμβολαίου και Καρτοκινητής που δεν έχουν ενεργοποιημένο κάποιο πρόγραμμα ή πρόσθετη υπηρεσία που να παρέχει πρόσβαση στο Internet.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Και πάλι, επιμένω, κανείς δεν με ρώτησε αν θέλω την αυτόματη ενεργοποίηση.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Τέλος, για να απαλαγείς από τις χρεώσεις (κάτι που θα έπρεπε να αναφέρεται και στα SMS που στέλνουν) απλά στείλε δωρεάν SMS με τις λέξεις END DAY στο 1333.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Update 30 Σεπτεμβρίου 2011]:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Το μύνημα ξαναεπέστρεψε (μαζί με την χρέωση).  Τώρα, και καλά, το έχουν &amp;ldquo;φτιάξει λίγο&amp;rdquo; γιατί μερικά δευτερόλεπτα μετά το πρώτο μύνημα (με το ΜΟΛΙΣ ΣΥΝΔΕΘΗΚΕΣ ΣΤΟ INTERNET κτλ κτλ) σου στέλνουν κι&amp;rsquo; άλλο μύνημα που λέει:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ΑΝ ΕΧΕΙΣ SMARTPHONE ΣΥΣΚΕΥΗ Η ΠΡΟΣΒΑΣΗ ΣΤΟ INTERNET ΙΣΩΣ ΟΦΕΙΛΕΤΑΙ ΣΕ ΕΦΑΡΜΟΓΕΣ (ΚΑΙΡΟΣ-ΝΕΑ-Ε-MAIL) ΠΟΥ ΣΥΝΔΕΟΝΤΑΙ ΑΥΤΟΜΑΤΑ. ΓΙΑ ΠΛΗΡΟΦΟΡΙΕΣ ΚΑΛΕΣΕ ΤΟ 13838&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Βασικά, δηλαδή, φταίει η συσκευή σου που είναι smartphone και έχει την απαίτηση να συνδεθεί στο internet.  Δεν φταίμε εμείς, η Cosmote, που ξεδιάντροπα αποφασίσαμε για σένα ότι θέλεις να χρεώνεσαι κάθε μέρα ένα ευρώ χωρίς να έχεις ερωτηθεί πρώτα! Όχι, μάλλον φταίνε οι εφαρμογές του τηλεφώνου σου.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Επίσης στο μύνημα που σου στέλνουμε ΔΕΝ σου λέμε πως να το απενεργοποιήσεις, αλλά πάρε μας τηλέφωνο να σε χρεώσουμε και γι&amp;rsquo;αυτό.  Άσε που μερικοί μπορεί και να μην το κάνουνε, οπότε θα συνεχίσουμε να τους χρεώνουμε τα ευρώ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Πήρα πάλι τηλέφωνο για να δώ πως τελικά απενεργοποιήται αυτό το πράγμα.  Για να σας γλυτώσω και τα άλλα 0.135€ που σε χρεώνουν στο 13838 (οι ρεζίληδες) οι οδηγίες είναι οι εξής:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(όπως είχα αναφέρει και πριν) Στέλνεις END DAY στο 1333.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Απαντάνε με:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ΤΟ ΑΙΤΗΜΑ ΣΑΣ ΕΙΝΑΙ ΥΠΟ ΕΠΕΞΕΡΓΑΣΙΑ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;και μετά από λίγο:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ΤΟ ΑΙΤΗΜΑ ΣΑΣ ΓΙΑ ΑΠΕΝΕΡΓΟΠΟΙΗΣΗ ΤΗΣ ΥΠΗΡΕΣΙΑΣ COSMOTE INTERNET DAY PASS ΟΛΟΚΛΗΡΩΘΗΚΕ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording Streaming Audio</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/04/recording_streaming_audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/04/recording_streaming_audio/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My choice of Ubuntu tools for recording, splitting and tagging streaming audio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;recording:614caedb33634d43f044cbd61067e96e&#34;&gt;Recording&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://streamripper.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;streamripper&lt;/a&gt;: Command line tool. Excellent choice since it makes it so easy to schedule recordings with it::&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ streamripper URL -d /home/stratos/outRec -l 7800 -d /dir/to/save -t &amp;ndash;xs-none&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-l 7800: The duration of the recording (in seconds)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-d /dir/to/save: Directory where to save the stream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-t: Do not overwrite files in recording folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ndash;xs-none: Do not try to find silent parts in the recording&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course adding to cron is quite easy::&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ crontab -e
  0 6 * * 1 streamripper URL -options for recording every Monday morning at 6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;splitting:614caedb33634d43f044cbd61067e96e&#34;&gt;Splitting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://audacious-media-player.org&#34;&gt;audacious&lt;/a&gt;: Audio player that has a nice Left-Right cursor key playback to easily find the places in the stream recording that you want to split/cut. Mark the Start and End Time from the recording that you made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mp3splt.sourceforge.net/mp3splt_page/home.php&#34;&gt;mp3spl&lt;/a&gt;: Using the Start and End Times from above, use them to split the recording. Don&amp;rsquo;t bother with the &lt;code&gt;mp3splt-gtk&lt;/code&gt; gui app::&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ mp3splt recording.mp3 65.36 124.33 -a -o finalRecording&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;65.36: The start time from the original recording that the split will start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;124.33: The end time from the original recording that the split will end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-a: This option will slightly adjust the start and end time to fall on a silent period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-o finalRecording: The final splitted file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tagging:614caedb33634d43f044cbd61067e96e&#34;&gt;Tagging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://easytag.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;easyTag&lt;/a&gt;: Use it to put mp3 tags in the final recording. Actually, any tagger would do. This is a, well, easy one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy recordings!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dune</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!--- 0441013597 --&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/5/5a/FrankHerbert_Dune_1st.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Frank Herbert&amp;#39;s Dune&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I was looking to print a nice PnP (Print and Play) game and I came across &lt;a href=&#34;http://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/121/dune&#34;&gt;Dune&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is &lt;a href=&#34;http://boardgamegeek.com/thread/531160/scotts-dune-build-project/page/1&#34;&gt;nicely redone&lt;/a&gt;, from it&amp;rsquo;s original 1979 publishing, so thick with theme from the book, that really made me wanna read the book again. First time I read it was while a was a freshman in university (back in &amp;lsquo;89).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, this book is often quoted as &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;THE best science fiction novel&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; with more than 12 million copies sold worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The [wikipedia article][] is very informative, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[wikipedia article]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dune_(novel&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dune_(novel&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert an A4 sized .pdf file to A5 size</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/01/convert_an_a4_page_to_a5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/2011/01/convert_an_a4_page_to_a5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was working on a LyX document based on the Tufte layout and unfortunately the page layout was available at A4 page sizes only (ok, US letter, too, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t count :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could try and learn Latex and create my own page size but the task looked monumental. I am sure the solution might be easy enough, but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it myself. Googling for A5 sized tufte layouts didn&amp;rsquo;t help either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to the command line it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From LyX export you final document to postscript format, let&amp;rsquo;s say myBook.ps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  psresize -Pa4 -pa5 myBook.ps myBook.A5.ps
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will convert the original .ps to another sized at A5. Unfortunately it will need further tweaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the myBook.A5.ps postscript file and delete the &lt;code&gt;% %DocumentMedia&lt;/code&gt; line (if one exists).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also change the existing &lt;code&gt;% %BoundingBox:&lt;/code&gt; line to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;% % BoundingBox: 0 0 421 595
% % DocumentPaperSizes: a5
% % BeginPaperSize: a5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; On a couple of documents I could not locate the &lt;code&gt;% %BoundingBox:&lt;/code&gt; line and the structure of the .ps file was a little weird. As a workaround try to edit the:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;% % BeginPaperSize: a5
/setpagedevice where
{ pop &amp;lt;&amp;lt; /PageSize [420 595] &amp;gt;&amp;gt; setpagedevice }
{ /a5 where { pop a5 } if }
ifelse
% % EndPaperSize
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;section. In it&amp;rsquo;s original format it will contain A4 references and the dimensions would be [595 842].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally create your PDF file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gs -dSAFER -dNOPAUSE -dBATCH -sDEVICE=pdfwrite \
-sPAPERSIZE=a5 -dPDFSETTINGS=/printer \
-dCompatibilityLevel=1.4 -dMaxSubsetPct=100 \
-dSubsetFonts=true -dEmbedAllFonts=true \
-sOutputFile=myBook.pdf myBook.A5.ps
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open myBook.pdf and marvel at your handiwork&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forever War</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/the_forever_war/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/the_forever_war/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/c/cd/TheForeverWar%281stEd%29.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The Forever War&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private William Mandella is a reluctant hero in an interstellar war against an unknowable and unconquerable alien enemy. But his greatest test will be when he returns home. Relativity means that for every few months&amp;rsquo; tour of duty centuries have passed on Earth, isolating the combatants ever more from the world for whose future they are fighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(From the book&amp;rsquo;s back cover)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow, this was a very nice read. I never thought of that particular aspect of time dilation, when travelling at the speed of light. Talking about a meaningless war that drags it&amp;rsquo;s feet&amp;hellip;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two thumbs up for &amp;ldquo;The Forever War&amp;rdquo;, On to &amp;ldquo;Forever Peace&amp;rdquo; now&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>