<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Scifi on Stratos Gerakakis </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/tags/scifi/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Stratos Gerakakis</author>
    
    <updated>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Left Hand Of Darkness</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/left_hand_of_darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Stratos Gerakakis</author>
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/left_hand_of_darkness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/8/88/TheLeftHandOfDarkness1stEd.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter is an Earth-like planet with two major differences: conditions are semi artic even at the warmest time of the year, and the inhabitants are all of the same sex. Tucked away in a remote corner of the universe, they have no knowledge of space travel or of life beyond their own world. And when a strange envoy from space brings news of a vast coalition of planets which they are invited to join, he is met with fear, mistrust and disbelief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(From the book&amp;rsquo;s back cover)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I barely had enough patience to finish this book. I wonder how come it got both the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nebula_Award&#34;&gt;Nebula&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hugo_Award&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; awards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was so special about the a single man trying to convince a newly discovered planet to join the Ekoumen (from the Greek word &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oikoumene&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;οικουμένη&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;)? It could have been vastly more interesting, but the pace and the subject matter of the character conversations were a complete turn off for me. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait for the book to finish. Good thing it was a short one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a nice Ursulla Le Guin book, you&amp;rsquo;re better off with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Earthsea&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Earthsea Trilogy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ringworld</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/ringworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Stratos Gerakakis</author>
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/ringworld/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!--- 0575077026 --&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/7/71/Ringworld%281stEd%29.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Ringworld&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No wonder this has won both Hugo and Nebula awards in &lt;sup&gt;1970&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;71&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not very fond of Niven&amp;rsquo;s writing style (this is the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Larry_Niven&#34;&gt;Larry Niven&lt;/a&gt; book I read) and maybe he used it for this book only.  The plot though was ingenious.  The idea of the Ringworld was very interesting. It kept me entertained from the beginning until the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended! :-)  Read more about the plot on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ringworld&#34;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Enough for Love</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/time_enough_for_love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Stratos Gerakakis</author>
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/time_enough_for_love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!--- 0441810764 --&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/6/68/Time_Enough_For_Love_73.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Time Enough for Love&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lazarus Long&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1916-4272&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The capstone and crowning achievement of Heinlein&amp;rsquo;s famous Future History, TIME ENOUGH FOR LOVE follows Lazarus Long through a vast and magnificent timescape of centuries and worlds.Heinlein&amp;rsquo;s longest and most ambitious work, it is the story of a man so in love with Life that he refused to stop living it; and so in love with Time that he became his own ancestor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(From the books back cover)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Heimlein is one of my favorite authors. &amp;ldquo;Time enough for Love&amp;rdquo; was nominated for the Nebula Award for Best Novel (1973) and the Hugo and Locus Awards (1974) and although did not finally win, nonetheless it is quite an interesting read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I cannot outdo the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_Enough_for_Love&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; about the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dune</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Stratos Gerakakis</author>
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!--- 0441013597 --&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/5/5a/FrankHerbert_Dune_1st.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Frank Herbert&amp;#39;s Dune&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking to print a nice PnP (Print and Play) game and I came across &lt;a href=&#34;http://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/121/dune&#34;&gt;Dune&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is &lt;a href=&#34;http://boardgamegeek.com/thread/531160/scotts-dune-build-project/page/1&#34;&gt;nicely redone&lt;/a&gt;, from it&amp;rsquo;s original 1979 publishing, so thick with theme from the book, that really made me wanna read the book again. First time I read it was while a was a freshman in university (back in &amp;lsquo;89).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, this book is often quoted as &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;THE best science fiction novel&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; with more than 12 million copies sold worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dune_(novel)&#34;&gt;wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; is very informative, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forever War</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/the_forever_war/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Stratos Gerakakis</author>
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/the_forever_war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/c/cd/TheForeverWar%281stEd%29.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The Forever War&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private William Mandella is a reluctant hero in an interstellar war against an unknowable and unconquerable alien enemy. But his greatest test will be when he returns home. Relativity means that for every few months&amp;rsquo; tour of duty centuries have passed on Earth, isolating the combatants ever more from the world for whose future they are fighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(From the book&amp;rsquo;s back cover)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow, this was a very nice read. I never thought of that particular aspect of time dilation, when travelling at the speed of light. Talking about a meaningless war that drags it&amp;rsquo;s feet&amp;hellip;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two thumbs up for &amp;ldquo;The Forever War&amp;rdquo;, On to &amp;ldquo;Forever Peace&amp;rdquo; now&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Demon Princes</title>
      <link>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/the_demon_princes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Stratos Gerakakis</author>
      <guid>http://stratos.gerakakis.net/book/the_demon_princes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!--- 0312853025 --&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirth Gersen carries in his pocket a slip of paper with a list of five names written on it. Theses are the names of the five Demon Princes who led the historic Mount Pleasant Massacre, which destroyed not only Kirth&amp;rsquo;s family but his entrire world as well. He roams the universe, searching the endless galaxies of space, hunting down the Demon Princes and exacting his revenge. Three princes will fall before Kirth&amp;rsquo;s work is done, and two more await their doom&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(from the book&amp;rsquo;s back cover)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Volume One that includes the first three books of the series: The Star King, The Killing Machine and The Palace of Love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;The Star King&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/48/Star_king.jpg/200px-Star_king.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The Star King&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
   

&lt;p&gt;Gesrhen is against Attel Malagate. Attel is not human, but rather a type of species, later called Star Kings, that can quickly mutate (through not so many generations) and approximate the best qualities of similar species that surrounds them. When humans colonized their planet, Star Kings quickly became a species that rivaled even human themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting concept in the book (apart from the detective work that Gershen has to go through to locate Attel) is Smade&amp;rsquo;s Planet and Smade&amp;rsquo;s Tavern. Smade, apparently fed up with society, took his family and set up a tavern, appropriately named Smade&amp;rsquo;s Tavern, on a remote uninhabited planet. The only inhabitants of the planet is Smade and his family running the tavern. The planet is locate Beyond (beyond the limits of what is considered explored civilized galaxy) and the tavern is patroned with fugitives and outlaws looking to relax a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smade runs a quite civil establishment and although his clientele is of doubtful morality, they must obey his rules or face his wrath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more at the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_King&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;The Killing Machine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/29/Killing_Machine_%28Jack_Vance%29_1st_edition.jpg/200px-Killing_Machine_%28Jack_Vance%29_1st_edition.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The Killing Machine&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
   

&lt;p&gt;The Killing Machine contains &lt;strong&gt;THE BEST&lt;/strong&gt; villain name I have ever read: &lt;strong&gt;Kokkor Hekkus&lt;/strong&gt;. It sounds so mean, that I do not even have to read a description of the vile things Mr.Hekkus has performed in his life. The fact that he is a &amp;ldquo;hormagaunt&amp;rdquo;, extending his life by stealing children and kind of &amp;ldquo;distilling&amp;rdquo; them (it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even sound nice), in order to extend his lifespan, doesn&amp;rsquo;t make him any more likable, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of the &amp;ldquo;Interchange&amp;rdquo; is the interesting fact of this book. Basically the Interchange, located in a secure planet, acts as an intermediary between kidnappers and ransomers. They safely keep the kidnapped victims and accept payments from their family that they forward to the kidnappers. Their motto is that everything is civilized and they offer the assurance and the much needed good faith that the whole procedure will be as smooth as possible with no surprises from either party. They take a cut of the ransom and try to be as civilized and humane to the kidnap victims. Since they guarantee such efficiency, it is to the best interest of everyone involved that they continue providing their services as is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more at the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Killing_Machine&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;The Palace of Love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/7a/Palace_of_love.jpg/200px-Palace_of_love.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The Palace of Love&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gershen is after Viole Falush on this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all due respect to Mr.Vance, this book hurt my head. Having to read through so much rumble from the mad poet Navarth (oh, he was quite mad, alright) was making me skip a page every so often just to get to the conclusion of it all. I had no interest at all on either Viole Falush, the plot as it was unfolding, or their dialogs, that were disjointed and led to no plausible or understandable conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My guess is, that even if you skip this book, in the Demon Princes pentalogy, you wont miss much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more at the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Palace_of_Love&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>